Guide to the Ford E. and Harriet R. Curtis Theatre Collection of Pittsburgh Performing Arts Photographs, 1914-present CTC.1966.03
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Productions, 1938-2011; I.; 1022 photographs
  - Glengarry Glen Ross, 2 photographs
    This folder contains two photographs from the Axiom Theatre's production of Glengarry Glen Ross.
  - God's Favorite, 2002; 1 photograph
    God's Favorite was presented by Mountain Playhouse from July 2-14, 2002. Photograph is of David Garwood and Nick Ruggeri.
  - Godspell - California University of Pennsylvania, 2 photograph
    Godspell was presented at the California University of Pennsylvania's Steele Auditorium. The actors appearing in these photos are Anna Lama, Victoria Cozzolino, Nathan Mello, Trevor Southworth, Tom Berger, and Ryan Victor Pierce. Members of the cast of Grease, which was also being performed by CalRep during the same time appear in one of the photos.
  - Godspell - Camelot Productions, 1975; 2 photographs
    This Camelot Productions performance of Godspell was performed from October 17 - November 16, 1975 at the Plaza Theatre. These photographs are of cast members Bill Castellino, Leland Gantt, Dorothy Stanley, Pat Cena, Joan Leavy, Joe Rupert, Dann Howard, Mary Lee Casey, Nan Sumner, and Bruce Pitney.
  - Godspell - Gargaro Productions, 1997; 5 photographs
    Photographs are of Daniel Krell, Sharon Connelly-Schaller, Rick Hearst, and cast. This Gargaro Production of Godspell was performed from March 26 - April 6, 1997 at the Byham Theatre.
  - Godspell - Hidden Valley Dinner Theatre, Upper St. Clair, 1 photograph
    This folder contains one photograph of the Hidden Valley Dinner Theatre's production of Godspell including Mark E. Connolly, Jeffrey Griglak, Tim Strong, James Steliotes, and David Novich.
  - The Good Woman of Setzuan, 1987; 1 photograph
    The Good Woman of Setzuan was presented by Carnegie-Mellon University from October 7-17, 1987 at the Kresge Theatre. This photograph is of cast members Bruce Fault, Laura Hunter, David Lockhart, and Adona Butler.
  - A Grand Night for Singing, 1997; 1 photograph
    A Grand Night for Singing was presented by Mountain Playhouse from October 1-12, 1997. Photograph is of Janet Dickinson, Tom J. Schaller, Tim Sheahan, Kathi Gillmore, and Judy Baird.
  - Greenwillow, 1975; 1 photograph
    This folder contains one photograph of the North Star Player's production of Greenwillow.
  - Guys and Dolls - Community College of Allegheny County, 1 photograph
    Photograph is of actress Mary Brady. This Community College of Allegheny College production was performed at the CCAC South Campus Summer Theatre.
  - Guys and Dolls - Carnegie Mellon University, 1 photograph
    Photograph is of Anne B. Kittredge and Burke Moses. This Carnegie Mellon University Repertory Theatre production was performed at the Kresge Theatre.
  - Guys and Dolls - White Barn Theatre, 1974; 2 photographs
    Guys and Dolls was presented by the White Barn Theatre from July 2-13, 1974. Photographs are of Jack Kelly, Herb Keller, and Alice Engleman.
  - The Habitation of Dragons, 1988; 2 photographs
    The Habitation of Dragons was presented by the Pittsburgh Public Theater from September 20 - October 23, 1988. Photographs are of Conrad McLaren, Eugenia Rawls, Hallie Foote, Stephen Robert Hanna, Matt Mulhern, and Mac Fleischmann.
  - Hair - Gargaro Productions, October 1997; 3 photographs
    Photographs are of Audra Blaser, Renata Carreon, and Jim Robinson. This Gargaro Production of Hair was performed from October 7 - 12, 1997 at the Byham Theatre.
  - Hair - Odd Chair Playhouse, 1975; 2 photographs
    Hair was presented by the Odd Chair Playhouse from June - July 13, 1975. Photographs are Michael Samreny, John Amplas, Paul Binotto, Elizabeth Austin, and John V. Fahey.
  - The Hairy Ape, 1987; 1 photograph
    The Hairy Ape was presented by the Pittsburgh Public Theater from September 22 - October 25, 1987. Photograph is of Jim Abele and L. Peter Callender.
  - Halcyon Days, 2003; 1 photograph
    This folder contains one image of the 2003 Pittsburgh Playhouse Repertory Company's production of Halcyon Days. The image features Joseph Hindy as Blonigen and Tracey D. Turner as Ruby. Photo courtesy of Lighthouse Photography.
  - Hamlet, 1 photograph
    Photograph is of Bill Caisley, Kashi Johnson, Ben Smith, David Nocinski, John Koch, Michelle Proctor, and KenYatta Rogers. This University of Pittsburgh Theatre production was performed at the Stephen Foster Memorial Theatre.
  - Hamletmachine, April 1995; 1 photograph
    Photograph is of the cast of Hamletmachine including Lissa Brennan, Jim Cook, Brian Czarniecki, Camille Faria, David Hugar, Ben Moore, Sally Randa, Paul Prochna, Bret Weisberger, and Kellee Van Aken. This production was performed from April 20 - 30, 1995 at the Pit Theater in Oakland.
  - Happy Birthday America, July 12, 1975; 1 photograph
    This folder contains one photograph of the cast from Hidden Valley Dinner Theatre's production of Happy Birthday America
  - Happy Days, 2 photographs
    Photographs are of Elisabeth Orion and Robert Parks. This City Theatre production was performed during the 1996-1997 season.
  - Hard Times - Mountain Playhouse, 1993; 1 photograph
    Hard Times was presented by Mountain Playhouse from September 22 - October 3, 1993. Photograph is of Larry John Meyers and Lee Brock.
  - Hard Times - Pittsburgh Playhouse Repertory Company, 2004; 4 photographs
    This folder contains four images of the 2004 Pittsburgh Playhouse Repertory Company's production of Hard Times. The first image features David Cabot as Josiah Bounderby and Susan McGregor-Laine as Mrs. Sparsit. The second and third images feature David Cabot as Josiah Bounderby, Christine Ryndak as Louisa Gradgrind Bounderby, and Robert Haley as Mr. Gradgrind. The fourth image features David Cabot as Josiah Bounderby, Susan McGregor-Laine as Mrs. Sparsit, and Philip Winters as Stephen Blackpool. Photos courtesy of Lighthouse Photography.
  - Heart and Soul, 1993; 2 photographs
    Heart and Soul was presented by Summer Theater-by-the-Grove at Indiana University of Pennsylvania from July 22-31, 1993. Photographs are of Klye Leigh McMahan, Brian O'Neill, and Matt Yeager.
  - Hedda Gabler, 1989; 1 photograph
    Photograph is of Helena Ruoti as Hedda. This Pittsburgh Public Theater production was performed from April 11 - May 14, 1989 at the Theodore L. Hazlett, Jr. Theatre.
  - A History of the American Film, 1983; 1 photograph
    A History of the American Film was presented by Pittsburgh Public Theater from October 28 - November 2, 1983. Photograph is of Holly Thuma, Carol Gustafson, and Hugh Rose.
  - Hold Me!, 1979; 2 photographs
    These two photographs show cast members of Hold Me!. Included in the photos are Robert Koch, Bonnie Gilmore, Fred Donatelli, and John Waterson. The Fine Line Theatre Company play was performed at the Lion Walk Performing Arts Center in Oakland November 2nd-24th, 1979.
  - A Hole in the Dark, 2001; 2 photographs
    Photographs are of Dale Soules and Ray Ford. This City Theatre production was performed from March 23 - April 15, 2001.
  - Holiday Snap, 1992; 1 photograph
    Photograph is of David A. Clark, Janet Dickinson, Cailen Larsen, and Tim Sheahan. This Mountain Playhouse production was performed from Jun 30 - July 12, 1992.
  - The Homecoming, 1975; 1 photograph
    The Homecoming was presented by the Pittsburgh Laboratory Theatre from November 20 - December 28, 1975. Photograph is of R.G. Caughey, Bob Elbaum, and Chris Blaety.
  - The Homecoming, 1981; 1 photograph
    The Homecoming was presented by the Pittsburgh Laboratory Theatre from October 24 - November 22, 1981. Photograph is of Bingo O'Malley and Phil Thomson.
  - Hot L Baltimore, 1995; 1 photograph
    Photograph is of Tami Dixon, Cristina Wager, Jane L. Moore, and Chris Hoch. This Carnegie Mellon Drama production was performed from October 27 - November 4, 1995 at the Kresge Theatre.
  - Hot Mikado, 1994; 1 photograph
    Hot Mikado was presented by the Civic Light Opera from June 14-19, 1994. Photograph is of Jim Corti and Avery Sommers.
  - How the Other Half Loves, 1980; 1 photograph
    How the Other Half Loves was presented by Mountain Playhouse in 1980. This photograph is of David Garwood and Kelly Champion.
  - How the Other Half Loves, 1994; 1 photograph
    How the Other Half Loves was presented by Mountain Playhouse from September 7-18, 1994. This photograph is of Scott Wakefield, David Garwood, Janet Dickinson, and Becky Moran.
  - I am the Brother of Dragons, 1983; 1 photograph
    I am the Brother of Dragons was presented by Saltworks Theatre Company in 1983. This photograph is of Patrick Dominguez.
  - I Do! I Do! - Mountain Playhouse, 1983; 1 photograph
    I Do! I Do! was presented by Mountain Playhouse from May 14-29, 1983. Photograph is of David Garwood and Suzanne Brian.
  - I Do! I Do! - Mountain Playhouse, 1992; 1 photograph
    I Do! I DO! was presented by Mountain Playhouse from September 30 - October 11, 1992. Photograph is of Judy Baird and Tim Sheahan.
  - I Do! I Do! - Pittsburgh Public Theatre, 1991-1992; 1 photograph
    Photograph is of Anthony Cummings and Ann Kittredge. This Pittsburgh Public Theater production was performed from November 27, 1991 - January 12, 1992.
  - I Do! I Do! - South Park Conservatory Theatre, 1985; 1 photograph
    I Do! I Do! was presented by the South Park Conservatory Theatre from July 25 - August 16, 1985. Photograph is of Gene Kail and Demetria Mellott.
  - I Hate Hamlet, 1995; 1 photograph
    I Hate Hamlet was presented at the Mountain Playhouse from June 6-18, 1995. This photograph is of Brian Robinson, Michele Schmitt, and Christopher Joseph.
  - I Love You, You're Perfect, Now Change, 2008; 15 photographs (on CD-R disc)
    The disc contains 15 images of the 2008 Civic Light Opera's production of I Love You, You're Perfect, Now Change. The first and second image are production photos. The following images are headshots as follows: Barbara Anderson, Tim Brady, James Brennan, Caitlin Reilly, Christine Laitta, Joe Domenic, Mark Tinkey, Kristiann Menotiades, Deana Muro, Andy Ostrowski, Andrea Shockling, and Ted Watts Jr. One image is of the show's logo. Photos courtesy of Matt Polk.
  - I Ought to be in Pictures - Mountain Playhouse, 1981; 1 photograph
    I Ought to be in Pictures was presented by Mountain Playhouse from September 30 - October 11, 1981. This photograph is of Shirley Brandon Bays and David Anthony.
  - I Ought to be in Pictures - Mountain Playhouse, 1991; 1 photograph
    Photograph is of Joe Muzikar, Lona Scavone, and Caitlin Larsen. This Mountain Playhouse production was performed in May of 1991.
  - I Ought to be in Pictures - White Barn Theatre, 1982; 1 photograph
    I Ought to be in Pictures was presented by the White Barn Theatre from September 10-25, 1982. Photograph is of Jude Pohl, Shirley Haviland, and Clara Gentile.
  - Images of Zora, 1995; 1 photograph
    Images of Zora, an exhibition of prints by Ann Tanksley based on the short stories of Zora Neale Hurston, was presented by City Theatre from February 24 - March 19, 1995. Photograph is of "Jumping at the Sun" print.
  - The Immigrant, 1989; 1 photograph
    The Immigrant was presented by the Pittsburgh Public Theater from January 3 - February 5, 1989. Photograph is of Richard Thomsen, Devora Millman, Bruce Nozick, and Carole Lockwood.
  - The Importance of Being Earnest - Community College of Allegheny College, 1978; 2 photographs
    The Importance of Being Earnest was presented by Community College of Allegheny County from August 17-26, 1978. Photographs are of Don Jukes, Catherine Robinson, Don DeTemple, Sue Huckestein, Kathy Chapman, and George Kenderes.
  - The Importance of Being Earnest - Mountain Playhouse, 2002; 1 photograph
    The Importance of Being Earnest was presented by the Mountain Playhouse in September 2002. Photographs are of Abe Reybold as Jack, Barbara Russell as Lady Bracknell, and Jenn Morse as Gwendolyn.
  - The Importance of Being Earnest - Point Park College, 2 photographs
    Photographs are of actors Melissa Young, Marie O'Brien, Steven Wilson, and Brian Barefoot. This was a Point Park College Theatre Company production.
  - The Importance of Being Earnest - Unseam'd Shakespeare Company, 2002; 1 photograph
    This production of The Importance of Being Earnest was performed by the Unseam'd Shakespeare Company at the Lester Hamburg Theatre, June 21st through July 6th, 2002. This photo shows actors Doug Mertz, Varian Huddleston, and Sheila McKenna. Photograph by Scott Bellinger.
  - In a Country Manor, 1994; 1 photograph
    In a Country Manor was presented by Summer Theater-by-the-Grove at Indiana University of Pennsylvania from July 7-16, 1994. Photograph is of Nina Leichtling, Melinda Bair, and Faith Farrell.
  - Indian Ink, August 2002; 1 photograph
    Indian Ink was presented by the Quantum Theatre at Allegheny Cemetery in August 2002. This photo includes actors Robin Walsh and Sanjit De Silva. Photograph by Mary Mervis.
  - Indians, 1974; 1 photograph
    Indians was presented by the Pittsburgh Poor Players from February 14 - March 9, 1974 at the University and City Ministries. Photograph is of John Dorish and Edith DeLisio.
  - Inherit the Wind, 1 photograph
    This Washington and Jefferson College Center Stage Players production was performed at W&J College.
  - Inspecting Carol, 1995; 1 photograph
    Photograph is of Joe Schulz, Renee Ann Keil, Rebecca Hunt, Joe Clement, Nardi Novak, and Doug Mertz. This Community College of Allegheny County production was performed December 1-2, 7-9, and 14-16, 1995 at the South Campus Theatre.
  - Interchangeable Parts, 1980; 1 photograph
    Interchangeable Parts was presented by the Iron Clad Agreement from September 18-28, 1980. Photograph is of Larry John Meyers and Ann Beigel.
  - Istanbul, June 1991; 1 photograph
    Photograph is of cast members of Istanbul. This Laurel Highlands Regional Theatre production was performed from June 6 - 30, 1991.
  - It Runs in the Family - Comtra, 1 photograph
    This file contains one photograph from Comtra Theatre's production of It Runs in the Family. Appearing in the photo are actors Ed Sipes, Dick Westerick, and Paul Laughlin. The play was performed in December of an unknown year.
  - It Runs in the Family - Mountain Playhouse, August 1992; 1 photograph
    Photograph is of David Garwood, Judy Baird, and Jeff Skowron. This Mountain Playhouse production was performed from August 18 - 30, 1992.
  - It's a Wonderful Life, The Musical, 1994; 1 photograph
    It's a Wonderful Life, The Musical was presented by the Saltworks Theatre Company from December 1-18, 1994 at the Eddy Theatre. This photograph is of Markus Zanders and Karla Rosenthal.
  - Jacques Brel is Alive and Well and Living in Paris, Sept. 1974; 10 photographs
    This folder contains ten photographs of Betty Caplan Production's Jacques Brel is Alive and Well and Living in Paris at the Oliver Plaza Dinner Theatre. The second and third photographs are of Lisby Larson. The fourth of John Appel, Charlotte Black, Terry Azzara, and Michael OConnell. The sixth of Lisby Larson, Joyce Levenson, and Curley. The seventh of Lisby Larson, John Appel, Franz Lion, and Joyce Levenson. The eighth of Joyce Levenson, Chris MacLaine, Giovanni Gioca, and Lynn Backstrom. The ninth of Joyce Levenson. The tenth of John Appel.
  - Jane Eyre, 2006; 3 photographs (on CD-R disc)
    These photographs are of Point Park University Conservatory of Performing Arts' production of Jane Eyre. The play was performed October 13th through November 5th, 2006. The images include actors Caroline Nicolian, Kalen J. Hall, and several other members of the cast. Note that there are also images from Point Park University Conservatory of Performing Arts' production of Ragtime. These images are duplicates.
  - The Jazz Singer, 2002; 10 photographs (on CD-R disc)
    This file contains a CD-R disc with 10 images from The Jazz Singer. The Jewish Theatre of Pittsburgh production played at the Katz Center for the Performing Arts at the Jewish Community Center of Greater Pittsburgh, October 31st through November 17th, 2002.
  - Jesse and the Bandit Queen, February 1990; 1 photograph
    Photograph is of Steve Jones. This Laurel Highlands Regional Theatre production was performed from February 1 - 25, 1990.
  - Jesus Christ Superstar - American Performing Arts Theatre Company, 1 photograph
    This folder contains one photograph of William Crowley in rehearsal for the American Performing Arts Theatre Company's Jesus Christ Superstar.
  - Jesus Christ Superstar - Byham, 1995-1996; 2 photographs
    Photographs are of Gargaro Productions of Jesus Christ Superstar. The 1995 photograph features Ray Cygrymus and the production was performed from April 5 - 15 at the Fulton Theatre. The 1996 photograph shows the cast and the production was performed from April 3 - 14 at the Byham Theatre (previously the Fulton Theatre).
  - Jesus Christ Superstar - Civic Light Opera, 1992; 2 photographs
    Photographs are of Kim Strauss and Carl Anderson. This Civic Light Opera production was performed from June 30 - July 12, 1992.
  - Joseph and the Amazing Technicolor Dreamcoat, December 1990; 1 photograph
    Photograph is of Katie Klump, Jim Critchfield, Valerie Komar, and Thoe Fried. This Gargaro Production was performed from December 5 - 31, 1990 at the Stephen Foster Memorial Theatre.
  - Jump Street, 1981; 2 photographs
    Jump Street was presented by Carnegie-Mellon University at the 1981 New Play Festival from March 30 - April 4, 1981. These photographs are of Stpehen Wardell, Tennyson Bardwell, Jeff Peters, Terri L. Brown, Kelvin Shepard, Sharon Porter, Maureen Quigley, Brian Varga, and Lisa Waltz.
  - Justice, May 1982; 1 photograph
    This photograph shows David Koch and an un-identified actress from the play Justice. The Fine Line Theatre Company production was performed in the St. Peter's Annex building May 7-30, 1982.
  - The Kermess, 1976; 6 photographs
    This production was presented by the Gavella Theatre of Yugoslavia at the Mellon Jr. High School in Mt. Lebanon from November 5-6, 1976.
  - Key Exchange, 1983; 1 photograph
    Included in this file is a photograph of Richard Willing, actor in the Fine Line Theatre Company's production of Key Exchange. The play was staged at the Famous Rider Cultural Center in Oakland, March 11th - April 3rd, 1983.
  - Kindertransport, 2 photographs
    This file contains 2 photographs from a Jewish Theatre of Pittsburgh production of Kindertransport. The photos show actors Demetria Mellott, Amy Guterson, and Laura Hillier.
  - The King and I, 1975; 3 photographs
    The King and I was presented by the White Barn Theatre from June 3-16, 1975. Photographs are of Vic Kleman, Ruth Cotton, and Mark Elcock.
  - The King and I, 1982; 1 photograph
    The King and I was presented by the White Barn Theatre from July 3-24, 1982. Photograph is of Tom Revilla.
  - King of Hearts, 2006; 2 photographs (on CD-R disc)
    This disc contains two images from the April 2006 Conservatory Theatre Company Point Park University's production of King of Hearts. The first images features Justin Peebles as Johnny Able, and the second images features Justin Peebles as Johnny Abel and Laura Veldheer as Jeunefille. Photos courtesy of Drew Yenchak, Lighthouse Photography.
  - Kiss Me Kate - Carnegie Mellon University, 1977; 1 photograph
    This Carnegie-Mellon University production of Kiss Me Kate was performed from February 10 - 19, 1977 at the Kresge Theatre. This photograph is of Charlotte Black, Dorothy Stanley, Paul Arthur Welterlen, and Ron Ferro.
  - Kiss Me, Kate - Indiana University of PA, July 1990; 2 photographs
    Photographs are of Beau Allen, Janet Rubinstein, Don Robinson, and Natalie Wolf. This Indiana University of Pennsylvania production was performed from July 5 - 14 as part of the Theater by the Grove summer performances.
  - Kiss Me Kate - Mountain Playhouse, 1983; 1 photograph
    Kiss Me Kate was presented by Mountain Playhouse from August 9 - September 4, 1983. Photograph is of director, Ken Barton, and choreographer, Bob Rizzo.
  - La Celestina, 1 photograph
    This folder contains one photograph of West Virginia University's production of La Celestina.
  - Ladies at Play, 1983; 2 photographs
    Ladies at Play was presented by the Pittsburgh Metropolitan Stage Company from June 11-25, 1983. Photographs are of Susan Chapek, Rosemary Hartup, and Shirley Tannenbaum.
  - Ladyhouse Blues, 2 photographs
    These photographs show actors Teri Bridgett as Liz and Marla Edgar as Dot in Ladyhouse Blues. The Community College of Allegheny County production was performed at the Boyce campus. The photographs were taken by David Holzemer.
  - Landscape of the Body, 1983; 1 photograph
    Landscape of the Body was presented by the Pittsburgh Laboratory Theatre from February 25 - March 27, 1983. Photograph is of Renee Henry.
  - Last Full Measure, 1938; 3 photographs
    Photographs are of cast members from the Sesqui-Centennial Allegheny County Fair production of Last Full Measure in September, 1938.
  - Lend Me A Tenor - Community College of Allegheny County, 1996; 2 photographs
    Photographs are of Ted Hoover, John Burja, and John Walter Klindworth. This Community College of Allegheny County production was performed From February 23 - March 9, 1996 at the CCAC South Campus Theatre.
  - Lend Me A Tenor - Comtra, 1 photograph
    This file contains one photograph from Comtra Theatre's production of Lend Me a Tenor. Appearing in the photo are actors Mike Byham, Mark Domencic, John Zuemie, Neil Keene, Eileen Hodgetts, Dolores Shawgo, and Susan Yoest. The play was performed in May of an unknown year.
  - Lenny - Odd Chair Playhouse, 1975; 1 photograph
    Lenny was presented by the Odd Chair Playhouse from July 16 - August 3, 1975. Photograph is of Peggy Greenberg and Ray Laine.
  - Lenny - Pittsburgh Laboratory Theatre, 1982; 4 photographs
    Lenny was presented by the Pittsburgh Laboratory Theatre from October 1-31, 1982. Photographs are of Jeff Paul, Caryl Opshinsky, Jerry Morris, and Richard Cavallucci.
  - Les Liaisons Dangereuses, 1990; 2 photographs
    Photographs are of Jack Wetherall, Funda Duyal, Drew McVety, and Camille Mitchell. This Pittsburgh Public Theater production was performed from February 15 - March 25, 1990 at the Theodore L. Hazlett, Jr. Theatre.
  - The Lesson, March 1997; 1 photograph
    Photograph is of Deborah Blazevich, Alyssa Jurewicz, and Paul Johns. This Community College of Allegheny College production was performed from March 20 - 22, 1997 at the CCAC Boyce Campus Theatre.
  - Lettice and Lovage, 1 photograph
    Lettice and Lovage was presented by Open Stage Theatre. Photograph is of Ellie Reese and Susan McGregor Laine.
  - Lie of the Mind, 2 photographs
    Photograph is of cast members of the 1990/1991 University of Pittsburgh, Studio Theatre production of Lie of the Mind.
  - Life with Father, Feb. 1984; 1 photograph
    This folder contains one photograph of Valley Players of Ligonier's production of Life with Father including Mary Lu George.
  - Life with Mother, 1994; 1 photograph
    Life with Mother was presented by Mountain Playhouse from July 12-24, 1994. Photograph is of Adam Bryant and Matt Bryant.
  - Light Up the Sky, 1976; 1 photograph
    Light Up the Sky was presented by the White Barn Theatre from June 15-26, 1976. Photograph is of Ginny Heller and Carol DePaul.
  - Light Up the Sky - Mattress Factory, 1981; 1 photograph
    This folder contains one photograph of the Mattress Factory's production of Light Up the Sky including Dean Hyland, Johnette Sullivan, and Joan Kimmel.
  - A Lion in Winter, 1989; 1 photograph